ほとんどすべての宗教は
Nearly all religions teach
that part of a person survives death.
人は死んでも何かが生き続ける
と教えています
でも 聖書は何と教えているでしょうか
But what does the Bible teach?
God created the first man, Adam,
from the dust.
神様は 最初の人間アダムを
土の塵でお造りになりました
He had the opportunity to live forever.
アダムは 永遠に生きられるはずでした
But when he deliberately disobeyed God,
しかし 神様に故意に背いたので
he was told that he would return to the dust
やがて塵に帰ると告げられました
存在しなくなるということです
—ceasing to exist.
では アダム以外の人は
どうなのでしょうか？
What about others who died after Adam?
When Jesus was told
イエスは 友人のラザロが
亡くなったと聞いた時
that his friend Lazarus died,
Jesus did not say
that Lazarus had gone to heaven.
ラザロが天へ行った
とは言いませんでした
Rather, he said:
代わりに「ラザロは休んでいます」
と言いました
“Our friend has fallen asleep.”
どういう意味だったのでしょうか？
What did he mean?
熟睡している人は
何かをすることもなければ
Just as someone in a deep sleep
is inactive
and unaware of his surroundings,
周りで起きていることにも
気づきません
the dead are not conscious
of anything at all.
それと同じで
死んだ人には何の意識もありません
さらに 眠っている人は
起こすことができます
Further, just as a person
can be awakened from a deep sleep,
the Bible shows that it is possible
to be awakened from death.
それと同じように
聖書によると
亡くなった人も
起こすことができます
Jesus did just that
イエスは ラザロに対して
そうしました
for his friend Lazarus.
Lazarus had been dead for four days.
ラザロが死んで
４日たっていました
If some part of Lazarus
ラザロの魂は死後も
天で生き続けていて
had survived his death
and gone to heaven,
イエスはラザロをそこから
呼び戻したということでしょうか？
would Jesus take him out of heaven
and force him to live on earth again?
No.
いいえ
ラザロは墓の中で
死の眠りに就いていました
Lazarus was asleep in the grave.
Jesus gave him back his life
イエスはラザロを生き返らせ
家族のもとに帰らせたのです
and reunited him with his family.
The Bible promises a time
聖書は 大勢の人が
when many people
will be resurrected from the dead,
ラザロのように復活する時が来る
と約束しています
just as Lazarus was.
Jesus spoke of this wonderful hope
when he said:
イエスはその素晴らしい見込み
について教え こう述べました
“The one who exercises faith in me,
even though he dies,
「わたしに信仰を働かせる者は
たとえ死んでも 生き返るのです」
will come to life.”
You may wonder:
では だれが生き返りますか
‘Who will return to life?
また 復活の備えはエホバについて
何を物語っていますか
And what does the resurrection
tell us about Jehovah God?’
Those questions are answered in lesson 6
これらの質問の答えは
「神からの良い知らせ」
という冊子の第６課にあります
of the brochure Good News From God!
You can download a copy from jw.org.
この冊子はjw.orgから
ダウンロードできます
エホバの証人は喜んで
聖書を学ぶお手伝いをいたします
Jehovah’s Witnesses would be happy
to study the Bible with you.
Fill in the online request for a Bible study,
jw.orgで聖書レッスンを
お申し込みください
and a Witness in your area
will call to discuss the Bible
お近くのエホバの証人が
ご都合のよい時間に
ご希望の場所へお伺いします
at a time and place convenient for you.